Contact

ashley.von630@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ashleyvon-0600a9239 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Regular Expressions (Regex)
Markdown
GitHub Gist

Ashley Von

HARD WIRED TO PROACTIVELY PERFORM AT THE HIGHEST LEVELS

Greater Tampa Bay Area

Summary

Meticulous innovator eager to bring 10 years of risk analysis and leadership in comprehension and ability to communicate and detail the global market, goals of the company I am committed to and representing, how to create a successful target of probability and clear evidence and corporate track on how to accomplish in my unique analysis, which is detailed and backed up in my experience.

Experience

Progressive Insurance Underwriter December 2017 - Present (6 years 10 months) St Petersburg, Florida, United States

- Success driven, has demonstrated 5 years of success in underwriting role
- Evaluated potential new business policies, binding guidelines of insurance agents to determine degree of risk
- Examined documents such as application forms, inspection reports, insurance maps, past claims, credit history, property appraisals to determine degree of risk from such factors as applicant financial standing, business operations, loss experience and value and condition of property
- · Determined whether to accept, modify or decline risks
- Evaluated debt ratio, loan-to-value ratios, credit scores property valuations and various other factors when making underwriting decisions
- Consulted with field representatives, insurance agents, or brokers, and other insurance or inspection companies to obtain further information, quote rates or explain company underwriting policies
- Managed requests for underwriting exceptions through compromise or accommodation when possible
- · Ensured both agent and company are met
- Analyzed credit, income, compliance, title documents and appraisals during underwriting process
- Supported review, acceptance, or denial of new or renewal business after carefully reviewing all information

- Participated in continuous improvement by generating suggestions, engaging in problem-solving activities to support teamwork
- Exceeded goals through effective task prioritization and great work ethic.

Ring

Data Engineer/ Lead Fraud Prevention Analyst September 2015 - December 2017 (2 years 4 months)

Santa Monica, California, United States

- I was hired as the 66th employee at Ring Video Doorbell at it's start up.
- I quickly adapted to and accepted the role to head up the fraud prevention team, building it person by person within the startup company and reduced fraud by 45% within 30 days.
- Analyzed large amounts of data to find patterns of fraud and anomalies as well as a procedures to offset to prevent it.
- Participated in data analysis and of installing Ring Video Doorbells in 41 of 400 homes in neighborhoods near Koreatown for free between July and December 2015.
- Burglaries were cut by more than 50% compared to surrounding neighborhoods over the same time frame within one year, which was information that was gathered processed, and used to project along with accordance of the L.A P.D. in order to reduce crime in similar areas.
- Investigated fraudulent claims, gathered, and submitted evidence for disputes, and set the foundation for the company's fraud prevention initiative.
- Worked for founder Jamie Siminoff, Vice President and Chief Operating Officer of the company, compiling data regarding multiple fraud analysis algorithms, companies, and strategies to prevent it based off trends.
- · Investigated cases of credit card fraud, which involved upwards of per case
- Contacted customers directly to notify of fraudulent activity and minimize impacts
- Collaborated with team members to discuss fraud trends and brainstorm methods to combat this type of crime
- Managed team of employees, overseeing hiring, training, and professional growth of employees with in the fraud team during these years.

City of Santa Monica Administrative Assistant II May 2015 - September 2015 (5 months)

Santa Monica, California, United States

06/2015 - 09/2015

- Organized, compiled, updated company personnel records for the city of Santa Monica
- Managed and updated HR databases with hires, terminations, investigations
- Prepared, and stored paperwork for HR policies and procedures
- Proofread, edited, published job descriptions
- · Supported staff as needed
- Executed record filing system to improve document organization and management
- Coached new employees on administrative procedures, company policies and performance standards
- Developed and updated spreadsheets and databases to track, analyze data
- Answered multi-line phone system, routing calls, delivering messages to staff and greeting visitors
- · Coordinated bookkeeping activities in QuickBooks.

SunTrust

Customer Service/ Corporate Fraud Investigator October 2013 - April 2015 (1 year 7 months)

Orlando, Florida, United States

- Consistently provided efficient, polite service to a diverse client base while promoting the SunTrust core values
- Metric-surpassing, showing a history of being promoted and adapting to new responsibilities
- Specialized in setting up new fraud claims and assessing existing cases with debit cards, credit cards, and ACH, including merchant disputes, associated with large scale corporation accounts, (i.e. Coca Cola)
- Cooperated with program administrators and clients to prevent and determine fraud
- Actively listened to customers' requests, confirming full understanding before addressing concerns
- Gathered evidence, written statements, financial documentation, and audio materials for examination.

New York & Company Assistant Manager April 2011 - September 2013 (2 years 6 months) St Augustine, Florida, United States

- Coordinated daily customer service operations
- Coached and supported new and existing employees
- Communicated with customers to ensure best experience possible

- Managed existing employees' schedules and make changes as needed
- Evaluated stores sales, prepared reports and suggested new ways to improve customer satisfaction and sales
- Collaborated and assisted the store manager in implementing sales projections and attracting customers
- Created reports, analyzed retail data, revues, competition, and expenses
- Conducted store/inventory audits
- Ensured all employees adhere to corporation's guidelines.

Education

Columbia University

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development · (April 2024 - October 2024)